<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>jf.h</title><link href="http://junfenglx.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://junfenglx.github.io/feeds/bi-ji.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://junfenglx.github.io/</id><updated>2015-04-15T12:25:16+08:00</updated><entry><title>The Little Redis Book 笔记</title><link href="http://junfenglx.github.io/the-little-redis-book-bi-ji.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-15T12:25:16+08:00</updated><author><name>junfeng</name></author><id>tag:junfenglx.github.io,2015-04-15:the-little-redis-book-bi-ji.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;query limitations, data structures and Redis' way to store data in memory&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;strings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;use cases: storing objects (complex or not) and counters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;hashes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hash suits for structed objects
hash implemention&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;sets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in op is O(1)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;use cases: Sets are great for tagging or tracking any other properties
of a value for which duplicates don't make any sense
(or where we want to apply set operations such as intersections and unions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;sorted sets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hashes are like strings but with fields,
then sorted sets are like sets but with a score&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;use cases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;leaderboard system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anything you want sorted by an some integer,
  and be able to efficiently manipulate based on that score,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pseudo Multi Key Queries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;using hashes to make querying a little easier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;References and Indexes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;manage/update/delete these references manually is defficult&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Round Trips and Pipelining&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Transactions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every Redis command is atomic, including the ones that do multiple things.
Additionally, Redis has support for transactions when using multiple commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Redis is actually single-threaded,
which is how every command is guaranteed to be atomic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;starts &lt;em&gt;multi&lt;/em&gt; then some &lt;em&gt;commands&lt;/em&gt; ends with exec or discard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Expiration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;commands:
- EXPIRE
- EXPIREAT
- TTL
- PERSIST
- SETEX&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ideal caching engine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lua Scripting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;keys with a TTL won't expire half-way through script execution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;lua-time-limit&lt;/em&gt; defines how long a Lua script is allowed to
execute before being terminated. Default is 5 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Replication&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Redis replication doesn't yet provide automated failover,
If the master dies, a slave needs to be manually promoted&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some commands are more expensive than others (sort for example)
and offloading their execution to a slave can keep the overall
system responsive to incoming queries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Backups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;disable both snapshotting and the append-only file (aof) on
the master and let a slave take care of this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Redis Cluster&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only will this offer horizontal scaling, including rebalancing,
but it'll also provide automated failover for high availability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;End&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Redis is easy to learn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;the real benefits Redis has to offer with its simplicity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Redis"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry></feed>